BRANDON GOTTSHALL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

blgottshall@gmail.com | (229) 412-6647 Github.com/Brandon-Gottshall LinkedIn.com/in/Brandon-Gottshall BrandonGottshall.com

PROFILE

A motivated Software Engineer with a highly adaptable skill set acquired through the Marine Corps and experience within the software industry. Comfortable taking root, and finding success in uncomfortable and difficult situations. Extremely passionate about the tech industry, and always ready to embrace failure, growth, and to demand success.

SKILLS

- Javascript
- Dart
- Ruby
- PostgreSQL
- Various No-SQL
- Flutter
- React
- NextJS
- Express
- Ruby on Rails
- Team-Player
- Receptive to Mentorship
- Professional Demeanor
- **Experience in Customer Service**
- Second Brain Evangelist

PROJECTS

COVID-19 TRACKER

Innovation Pharmaceuticals Inc.

Visualization of COVID-19 statistics. Includes a static animated graph.

- NextJS/React
- Tailwind CSS
- Rebuilt daily using CRON job

HR COMPANY SITE

Strategy HR

Customer facing site for an HR consulting firm in Brooklyn NY

- NextJS/React
- Tailwind CSS
- Serverless Functions

NYC CRIME VISUALIZED

Personal

Chronological visualization of NYC crime.

- React
- MapBox
- NYC openData

WORK EXPERIENCE

2020-2021 TECHNICAL CO-FOUNDER

Effortless Development

Brooklyn, NY & Remote

• Made Technical/Architecture decisions with my partner and my New York-Based Software Development Agency.



Planning: Built skills to rationally approach and make architecture decisions.



2019-2020 SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FELLOW

General Assembly

New York, NY

Cherry Point, NC

Full-time fellow in the Software Engineering Immersive program that includes over 400 hours of professional training over 12 weeks.

o Teamwork: Collaborated with UX design team to recreate and add accessability features to Booking.com



2015-2019 ASSISTANT MAINTENANCE SUPERVISOR

• Corporal (NCO in USMC) | Engineer Electrical Systems Technician

- o Oversaw maintenance and deployment of life-sustaining Marine Corps utilities gear, while mentoring, coaching, and leading Jr. Marines.
- Prioritized, coordinated and supervised maintenance personnel while maintaining total equipment readiness.
- **Dependability:** Maintained over \$7,000,000 worth of equipment
- Communication: Regularly coordinated events to move equipment for deployment and repair..



EDUCATION

WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY

BCS in Cloud Computing (2021-Present) Current

BROOKLYN COLLEGE

Computer Science (2020-2020) 12 Credits

AMERICAN INTERCONTINENTAL UNIVERSITY

90 Credits Information Technology (2018 - 2019)

SOFTWARE BOOTCAMP

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Software Engineering Immersive

2020 Certificate of Completion

United States Marine Corps